Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have part two of our series about small talk in English.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来关于英语闲聊系列的第二部分。
That's right.
没错。
So as we mentioned, small talk are very short, quick conversations about everyday things
正如我们提到的，闲聊是关于日常琐事的简短、快速的对话，
like the weather and usually have this with a colleague very quickly or a friend maybe.
比如天气，通常和同事或朋友快速聊一聊。
Yeah, maybe not someone you know very well too.
是啊，也可能是不太熟的人。
Exactly.
正是。
So we're going to take a look at part two.
那我们来看看第二部分。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue and see what's going on.
我们不如听一下对话，看看发生了什么。
So Michelle, let me introduce you to Maria.
那么Michelle，让我把你介绍给Maria。
She's my colleague from Brazil.
她是我来自巴西的同事。
Maria, this is Michelle.
Maria，这是Michelle。
Hi Michelle.
嗨，Michelle。
So what do you do here in Shanghai?
那你在上海做什么？
I mean, what work do you do?
我是说，你做什么工作？
I work in advertising right now.
我现在做广告行业。
How about you?
你呢？
I'm actually in the wine business.
我实际上在葡萄酒行业。
Oh, that sounds really great.
哦，听起来真不错。
I love wine myself.
我自己也喜欢葡萄酒。
Is this your first time to Shanghai, Maria?
这是你第一次来上海吗，Maria？
No, actually I often visit.
不，实际上我经常来。
I usually come to China for business at least once a year.
我通常每年至少来中国出差一次。
Also I love the restaurants in Shanghai.
而且我喜欢上海的餐厅。
So that's a good reason to come.
所以这也是来的好理由。
Me too.
我也是。
Actually, there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend.
实际上，我推荐一家很棒的巴西餐厅。
I mean, the food is delicious, but the service isn't so good.
我是说，食物很美味，但服务不太好。
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there.
我经常喜欢和朋友聚在一起，在那里吃烧烤。
We should go there together sometime.
我们应该找个时间一起去那里。
Wonderful idea.
好主意。
I'd love that.
我很乐意。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of these very interesting phrases we find in this dialogue
现在让我们看看对话中一些非常有趣的短语，
in Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first phrase we have today is from the first sentence of this dialogue.
今天我们第一个短语来自对话的第一句话。
James says, so Michelle, let me introduce you to Maria.
James说：“那么Michelle，让我把你介绍给Maria。”
That's right.
没错。
And the second phrase, introduce someone to or introduce you to.
第二个短语是“介绍某人给”或“把你介绍给”。
Okay, let me introduce you to this person.
好的，让我把你介绍给这个人。
So Marco, let me introduce you to my friend.
那么Marco，让我把你介绍给我的朋友。
Right.
对。
And this is something that you say when you want to tell the person, look, you're going
这是当你想要告诉对方“看，你要认识一个新朋友”时说的话。
to meet someone new.
你要认识一个新朋友。
Let me introduce you to my friend, Sally.
让我把你介绍给我的朋友Sally。
And this is very important because it's polite and it's a way for you to say, okay, you two
这很重要，因为它很礼貌，也是一种方式让你说：“好了，你们俩不认识彼此。”
don't know each other.
你们俩不认识彼此。
Here, this is this person's name, this is this person's name.
这是这个人的名字，这是这个人的名字。
It's very important when you are introducing people or when you're in a situation with
当你介绍别人时，或者当你和两个不认识彼此的人在一起时，这非常重要。
two people who don't know each other.
两个不认识彼此的人。
That's right.
没错。
Exactly.
正是。
So let me introduce you to someone.
所以让我把你介绍给某人。
Now another key question here, I think probably one of the key questions when you meet someone
现在另一个关键问题，我认为可能是当你认识新朋友时的一个关键问题，你在聊天、闲聊、简短对话中，“你在这里做什么”或“你是做什么的？”
new, you're talking, small talk, short conversation, what do you do here or what do you do?
你是做什么的？
What do you do?
So this might sound like a very strange question.
这听起来可能是个很奇怪的问题。
What do you do?
你是做什么的？
Do you watch TV?
你看电视吗？
Do you like to eat food?
你喜欢吃东西吗？
No, but this means what job do you do?
不，但这意思是“你做什么工作？”
Right.
对。
What type of work do you do?
你做什么类型的工作？
Okay.
好的。
So Marco, what do you do?
那么Marco，你是做什么的？
I host an English podcast.
我主持一个英语播客。
All right.
好的。
Me too.
我也是。
So this is the question.
所以这就是这个问题。
Now don't get confused and remember that this is the typical way of asking someone what
现在别搞混了，记住这是问别人工作的典型方式。
is their job.
问别人工作。
If you say, what is your job or what is your occupation, what is your occupation?
如果你说“你的工作是什么”或“你的职业是什么”，“你的职业是什么？”
It's too formal and it's kind of awkward.
那太正式了，而且有点尴尬。
I don't think anyone has ever asked me what is your occupation.
我想没人问过我“你的职业是什么”。
Now I rarely say that.
我很少这么说。
I almost always say, what do you do?
我几乎总是说“你是做什么的？”
Or maybe what type of work do you do?
或者“你做什么类型的工作？”
Or what business are you in?
或者“你从事什么行业？”
So this is our next phrase actually.
所以这其实是我们的下一个短语。
Right.
没错。
If someone asks you what business are you in or what industry are you in, you would
如果有人问你从事什么行业或属于哪个领域，你会
say like in this case, Maria, she is in the wine business.
像这个例子中，玛丽亚，她从事葡萄酒行业。
Okay.
好的。
I'm in the wine business.
我从事葡萄酒行业。
That means that my job has to do with selling or buying wine.
这意味着我的工作与买卖葡萄酒有关。
So if we replace the noun wine with something else, for example, clothing.
所以如果我们把名词“葡萄酒”换成别的东西，比如“服装”。
I'm in the clothing business or I'm in the cheese business.
我从事服装行业，或者我从事奶酪行业。
Exactly.
完全正确。
You can basically change it with anything.
你基本上可以换成任何东西。
With any product.
任何产品。
I guess if you sell computers, I'm in the computer business.
我想如果你卖电脑，就说我从事电脑行业。
Or if you have anything to do with computers, you can say I'm in the computer business.
或者如果你和电脑有关，你可以说我从事电脑行业。
All right.
好的。
So that's great.
那很棒。
I'm in the hmm business.
我从事嗯……行业。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right.
好的。
So now we know what the person does.
现在我们知道这个人做什么了。
We continue asking questions.
我们继续问问题。
You know, we're interested.
你知道，我们很感兴趣。
We want to keep the conversation going a little while longer.
我们想让对话再持续一会儿。
We say, Oh wow, that's really great.
我们说，哦哇，那真的很棒。
I love wine myself.
我自己也喜欢葡萄酒。
Then we ask, is this your first time to Shanghai?
然后我们问，这是你第一次来上海吗？
Okay.
好的。
So is this your first time to Shanghai or in Shanghai?
所以是“这是你第一次来上海”还是“在上海”？
This means is this your first time to visit Shanghai?
这意味着这是你第一次访问上海吗？
That's right.
没错。
The preposition here is always confusing for an ESL learner because sometimes do you say,
这里的介词对英语学习者来说总是很困惑，因为有时你会说，
is this your first time in Shanghai?
这是你第一次在上海吗？
Is this your first time on Shanghai?
这是你第一次在上海上面吗？
Now we're saying to Shanghai.
现在我们说“来上海”。
So in this case or in this type of question, both are correct.
所以在这种情况下或这类问题中，两种说法都正确。
Is this your first time in Shanghai?
这是你第一次在上海吗？
Is this your first time to Shanghai?
这是你第一次来上海吗？
All right.
好的。
So I could also say, you know, if we're in Chicago, Hey Marco, is this your first time
所以我也可以说，你知道，如果我们在芝加哥，嘿马可，这是你第一次
in Chicago?
在芝加哥吗？
But I have to ask if we are in that city.
但我必须问我们是否在那个城市。
I can't say, okay, I'm in Chicago today, but Marco, is this your first time in New York?
我不能说，好吧，我今天在芝加哥，但马可，这是你第一次在纽约吗？
Because we're not in New York right now.
因为我们现在不在纽约。
That could be confusing.
那可能会让人困惑。
So remember when you ask this question, you're asking about where you are today, right now.
所以记住，当你问这个问题时，你问的是你今天、现在所在的地方。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Very good.
非常好。
So on that note, let's take a break.
那么就此打住，我们休息一下。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with some more phrases.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后我们会回来讲更多短语。
So Michelle, let me introduce you to Maria.
所以米歇尔，让我介绍你认识玛丽亚。
She's my colleague from Brazil.
她是我来自巴西的同事。
Maria, this is Michelle.
玛丽亚，这是米歇尔。
Hi, Michelle.
嗨，米歇尔。
So what do you do here in Shanghai?
那么你在上海做什么？
I mean, what work do you do?
我是说，你做什么工作？
I work in advertising right now.
我现在做广告工作。
How about you?
你呢？
I'm actually in the wine business.
我其实在葡萄酒行业。
Oh, that sounds really great.
哦，那听起来真的很棒。
I love wine myself.
我自己也喜欢葡萄酒。
Is this your first time to Shanghai, Maria?
这是你第一次来上海吗，玛丽亚？
No, actually, I often visit.
不，其实我经常来。
I usually come to China for business at least once a year.
我通常每年至少来中国出差一次。
Also I love the restaurants in Shanghai.
而且我喜欢上海的餐厅。
So that's a good reason to come.
所以这是个来的好理由。
Me too.
我也是。
Actually, there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend.
其实，我推荐一家很棒的巴西餐厅。
I mean, the food is delicious, but the service isn't so good.
我是说，食物很美味，但服务不太好。
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there.
我经常喜欢和朋友聚在一起，在那里享受烧烤。
We should go there together sometime.
我们应该找个时间一起去那里。
Wonderful idea.
好主意。
I'd love that.
我很乐意。
All right, let's take a look at three more key phrases on Fluency Builder Part 2.
好的，让我们看看流利度提升第二部分中的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder So one phrase that we heard from this when
流利度提升 所以从这段对话中我们听到的一个短语是，当
things started to get a little bit more personal, Michelle said, I often like to get together
话题开始变得更私人时，米歇尔说，我经常喜欢
with friends.
和朋友聚在一起。
So this phrase here is to get together with friends.
所以这个短语是“和朋友聚在一起”。
So to get together means to be united or go with friends somewhere.
所以“聚在一起”意思是联合或和朋友一起去某个地方。
That's right.
没错。
So we could also use the phrase to hang out.
所以我们也可以使用短语“一起出去玩”。
This means you're not doing anything in particular.
这意味着你没有在做什么特别的事情。
You're not cooking or swimming or going shopping, but it just means you're together with your
你没有在做饭、游泳或购物，只是意味着你和你的
friends.
朋友们在一起。
You could be doing anything.
你可以做任何事情。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So even if you want to ask your friend or colleague, hey, do you want to get together
所以即使你想问你的朋友或同事，嘿，你想下班后
after work and have a couple of drinks?
聚一聚，喝几杯吗？
All right, that means would you like to hang out or would you like to go somewhere for
好的，那意思是“你想一起玩”或“你想去某个地方
a drink?
喝一杯吗？”
It's very informal and it's not romantic.
这非常随意，而且不是浪漫的。
It's just with friends.
只是和朋友一起。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you ask someone to get together sometime, it doesn't mean let's go out on a date.
所以如果你邀请某人“sometime get together”，并不意味着去约会。
It just means let's hang out.
只是意味着一起玩。
Let's hang out.
一起玩。
Let's be friends.
做朋友。
Okay.
好的。
Now, so they were talking about a Brazilian restaurant and James said, hey, we should
现在，他们正在谈论一家巴西餐厅，詹姆斯说，嘿，我们应该
go there sometime.
改天去那里。
Okay, we should go there together sometime is even more personal.
好的，“我们应该改天一起去那里”更个人化。
This is a really common phrase and one that you guys should remember as a phrase.
这是一个非常常见的短语，你们应该把它作为一个短语记住。
We should go there sometime.
我们应该改天去那里。
That means that I would like to make plans with you to go to this restaurant.
这意味着我想和你计划去这家餐厅。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
Now, if you notice the word sometime is separated.
现在，如果你注意，“sometime”这个词是分开的。
You have some and then apart, the other word is time.
有“some”和分开的另一个词“time”。
So it's very different from sometimes.
所以它和“sometimes”非常不同。
Don't confuse it.
不要混淆。
What we're saying here is when you have time, when I have time, we should go there.
我们在这里说的是，当你有时间，当我有时间时，我们应该去那里。
It's almost like saying one time or in the future.
这几乎就像说“某一次”或“将来”。
Sometimes is different.
“Sometimes”是不同的。
It's like I brush my teeth sometimes.
就像“我有时刷牙”。
That means that, not very often.
那意味着，不经常。
No, that's not true.
不，那不是真的。
But I would like to go there sometime means, you know, it's a little bit vague.
但“我想改天去那里”意味着，你知道，有点模糊。
I don't say when, but I would like to in the future.
我没有说什么时候，但我想将来去。
Exactly.
没错。
And Michelle agrees.
米歇尔同意了。
She says, well, it's a wonderful idea.
她说，嗯，这是个好主意。
I'd love that.
我很喜欢。
Okay.
好的。
This is another great phrase.
这是另一个很好的短语。
Remember this as a phrase.
把这个作为一个短语记住。
Would you like to go see a movie?
你想去看电影吗？
I'd love that.
我很喜欢。
So I'd love that.
所以“我很喜欢”。
I'd love to.
“我很乐意”。
These are ways of saying I like the idea.
这些都是表达“我喜欢这个主意”的方式。
Let's do it.
我们去做吧。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's usually in response to an invitation or suggestion.
所以这通常是对邀请或建议的回应。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a look at our dialogue again and review everything and we'll be back in
那么让我们再看一遍我们的对话，复习所有内容，我们一会儿
a bit.
回来。
So Michelle, let me introduce you to Maria.
米歇尔，让我介绍你认识玛丽亚。
She's my colleague from Brazil.
她是我来自巴西的同事。
Maria, this is Michelle.
玛丽亚，这是米歇尔。
Hi Michelle.
嗨，米歇尔。
So what do you do here in Shanghai?
那么你在上海做什么？
I mean, what work do you do?
我是说，你做什么工作？
I work in advertising right now.
我现在做广告工作。
How about you?
你呢？
I'm actually in the wine business.
我实际上在做葡萄酒生意。
Oh, that sounds really great.
哦，听起来真不错。
I love wine myself.
我自己也喜欢葡萄酒。
Is this your first time to Shanghai, Maria?
这是你第一次来上海吗，玛丽亚？
No, actually, I often visit.
不，实际上我经常来。
I usually come to China for business at least once a year.
我通常每年至少来中国出差一次。
Also I love the restaurants in Shanghai.
而且我喜欢上海的餐厅。
So that's a good reason to come.
所以这是个来的好理由。
Me too.
我也是。
Actually, there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend.
实际上，我推荐一家很棒的巴西餐厅。
I mean, the food is delicious, but the service isn't so good.
我是说，食物很美味，但服务不太好。
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there.
我经常喜欢和朋友聚在一起，在那里吃烧烤。
We should go there together sometime.
我们应该改天一起去那里。
Wonderful idea.
好主意。
I'd love that.
我很喜欢。
All right.
好的。
So as we can see, it's very quick, small conversation, but very good phrases to talk to a stranger,
所以我们可以看到，这是一个很简短的小对话，但里面有很多很好的短语，可以用来和陌生人交谈，
to start up a small conversation.
开启一段简短的对话。
I think these are great too, Marco, because if you're learning English and you want to
我觉得这些也很棒，Marco，因为如果你正在学英语，并且想
practice your speaking skills, you're not going to have many people to talk about deep
练习口语技能，你不太可能有很多人可以聊一些深奥的
things with.
话题。
So it's great to use with strangers or with people in your office.
所以用这些短语和陌生人或者办公室里的同事聊天非常合适。
That's right.
没错。
And these are common, typical questions.
而且这些都是常见、典型的问题。
And they're also appropriate to ask someone.
它们也很适合用来问别人。
So obviously, if you meet someone new, you're not going to ask them how much money they
所以显然，如果你遇到一个新朋友，你不会问他们赚多少钱，
make because that's kind of inappropriate in Western culture.
因为在西方文化中，这有点不太合适。
That's right.
没错。
So what we've taught you here are very polite, very common phrases.
所以我们在这里教你的都是非常礼貌、非常常见的短语。
We hope, hope, hope that you'll go out and practice these.
我们希望，希望，希望你能走出去练习这些。
If you have questions or comments, don't hesitate to leave them for us.
如果你有问题或评论，请随时给我们留言。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候在那里见。
Bye.
再见。
¡chao!
再见！